Guide to the Gay Men's Health Crisis records
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.
- Series XII. Public Policy Department, 1983-1997, n.d.; 38.75 boxes
  - XII. D. Organizations File, 1983-1993; 14 boxes
    - New York State AIDS Institute
      - Financial information, 1986-1988 (Box 388, Folder 7)
      - Meetings, 1986-1988 (Box 388, Folder 8)
      - Programs, 1986-1989 (Box 388, Folder 9)
      - Status report, 1991 (Box 388, Folder 10)
    - New York State Division of Human Rights, 1986-1989 (Box 388, Folder 11-12)
    - New York State Health Care Campaign, 1986-1992 (Box 389, Folder 1)
    - New York State Lesbian and Gay Lobby
      - General, 1990 (Box 389, Folder 2)
      - Division of Human Rights, 1988-1990 (Box 389, Folder 3-4)
      - Lobby Day, 1988 (Box 389, Folder 5)
    - New York Statewide Professional Standards Review Council, 1989 (Box 389, Folder 6)
    - Nonprofit Coordinating Committee of New York, 1990-1991 (Box 389, Folder 7)
    - OSHA Workplace Guidelines, 1989 (Box 389, Folder 8)
    - Parents and Friends of Lesbians and Gays, 1988 (Box 389, Folder 9)
    - Partnership for the Homeless, 1990 (Box 389, Folder 10)
    - People with AIDS Coalition
      - General, 1986 (Box 389, Folder 11)
      - Papers and newslines, 1986-1987 (Box 389, Folder 12)
    - Planned Parenthood of New York City, 1987, 1990 (Box 389, Folder 13-14)
    - Positive Action of New York, 1990 (Box 389, Folder 15)
    - Prenatal Care Steering Committee and Coalition to Fight Infant Mortality, 1986-1989 (Box 389, Folder 16-18)
    - Presidential Commission on the HIV Epidemic
      - Conference calls, 1988 (Box 389, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 390, Folder 1-2)
      - In-kind contributions, 1987-1988 (Box 390, Folder 3)
      - Ken South and Barry Gaspard, 1987-1988 (Box 390, Folder 4)
      - Member writings, 1987 (Box 390, Folder 5)
      - Member lists and biographies, 1988? (Box 390, Folder 6)
      - Testimony, 1988 (Box 390, Folder 7)
    - Project Inform, 1986-1987 (Box 390, Folder 8)
    - Public Citizen Health Research Group, 1988 (Box 390, Folder 9)
    - Public Health Council, 1989-1990 (Box 390, Folder 10)
    - Public Health Service, 1990-1991 (Box 390, Folder 11)
    - Public Interest Health Consortium for New York City, 1985-1986 (Box 390, Folder 12)
    - PWA Health Group, 1989-1992 (Box 390, Folder 13)
    - San Francisco AIDS Foundation, 1988-1990 (Box 390, Folder 14)
    - The State Employees Federated Appeal and the United Way, 1989 (Box 390, Folder 15)
    - Staten Island AIDS Task Force, 1990 (Box 390, Folder 16)
    - Statewide Emergency Network for Social and Economic Security (SENSES), 1990 (Box 390, Folder 17)
    - United for AIDS Action
      - General, 1992-1993 (Box 390, Folder 18)
      - Posters
        - 1992
        - 1992 (Box X-14)
    - United Hospital Fund, 1988 (Box 390, Folder 19)
    - United State Congress Senate Committee on Appropriations, 1989 (Box 390, Folder 20)
    - Village Nursing Home, 1987-1990 (Box 390, Folder 21)
    - Visiting Nurse Service of New York, 1986 (Box 391, Folder 1)
    - The War Conference, 1987-1988 (Box 391, Folder 2)
    - Women and AIDS Resource Network (WARN), 1987-1989 (Box 391, Folder 3)
  - XII. E. Topical Files, 1987-1993; 1.5 box
    This subseries contains the Topical Files of the Public Policy Department and includes files on legislation related to HIV/AIDS and correspondence and reports on needle exchange policies and programs.
    - ACT-UP and CDC Definitions of AIDS, 1991-1993 (Box 391, Folder 4-5)
    - AIDS voting guide, 1994 (Box 391, Folder 6)
    - GMHC Substance Abuse Services, 1991-1993 (Box 391, Folder 7)
    - Housing, 1991 (Box 391, Folder 8)
    - Insurance, 1990-1992 (Box 391, Folder 9-10)
    - Legislation
      - Abandoned infants (H.R. 3009), 1987 (Box 391, Folder 11)
      - AIDS Research and Information (S 1220), 1988 (Box 391, Folder 12)
      - D'Amato AIDS Bill (S 1374), 1987 (Box 391, Folder 13)
      - Helms Amendment (#963), 1987 (Box 391, Folder 14)
      - Orphan Drug Act, 1989-1990 (Box 391, Folder 15)
    - Medical, 1991-1993 (Box 391, Folder 16)
    - Needle Exchange
      - 1988-1990 (Box 391, Folder 17)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 392, Folder 1-2)
    - New York City Legislation, 1988 (Box 392, Folder 3)
    - Nursing Home Community Coalition of New York State, 1991-1992 (Box 392, Folder 4)
    - Social Security Administration, 1991-1992 (Box 392, Folder 5)
    - Substance Abuse, 1991 (Box 392, Folder 6)
    - Treatment, 1991-1992 (Box 392, Folder 7)
    - Women, 1991-1992 (Box 392, Folder 8)
- Series XIII. Staff Groups and Events, 1987-1995, n.d.; 2 boxes
  This series contains correspondence, memoranda, minutes, and other material from various Staff Groups and Events at GMHC. Included are agenda, memoranda, and minutes related to meetings attended by and memoranda sent to the entire staff; minutes from meetings of the Assistant Directors Group; flyers from miscellaneous staff groups at GMHC announcing classes, support groups, events, and special offers for staff members; memoranda and minutes of meetings of the Staff Caucus, created in 1989 to improve communication between the staff and management of GMHC; and material from the Union Organizing Committee.
  - All Staff, 1987-1993
    - Meetings, 1987-1993
      - Agenda, 1987-1993 (Box 392, Folder 9-10)
      - Memoranda, 1988 (Box 392, Folder 11)
      - Minutes
        - 1987 (Box 392, Folder 12)
        - 1989-1991 (Box 393, Folder 1)
    - Memoranda, 1989-1993
      - 1989-1993 Oct (Box 393, Folder 2-11)
      - 1993 Nov-Dec (Box 394, Folder 1)
  - Assistant Directors Group, 1992-1994
    The Assistant Directors Group consisted of assistant directors from all departments of GMHC who met to discuss staff issues, updates for departments, and other topics. All assistant directors were welcome to attend the meetings but not all did.
    - Memoranda, 1991-1993 (Box 394, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, 1992-1994 (Box 394, Folder 3-5)
  - Miscellaneous Groups, 1992-1993 (Box 394, Folder 6)
  - Staff Caucus, 1989-1993
    The Staff Caucus was created in 1989 to improve communication between the staff and management of GMHC. All staff members were welcome to join and representatives were elected from each department.
    - Memoranda, 1989-1993 (Box 394, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 1989-1993 (Box 394, Folder 8)
  - Union Organizing Committee, 1990-1995, n.d.
    The Union Organizing Committee developed in 1993 from the Staff Caucus and attempted to organize under Local 1199 United Healthcare Workers. The Committee sought to strengthen the job security, bargaining strength, and voice of the staff. Issues of racism, job security, and the attitude of the management towards the Staff Caucus led to this unionization attempt. The unionization vote was held on February 4, 1994, resulted in a split decision, and the staff did join Local 1199.
    - Complaints brought against GMHC, 1991-1994 (Box 394, Folder 9)
    - Flyers, 1993-1994 (Box 394, Folder 10)
    - Memoranda, 1993-1994 (Box 394, Folder 11-12)
    - Notes, 1990-1995, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 1-3)
    - Publicity, 1993-1994 (Box 395, Folder 4)
    - Report on health care benefits, 1994 (Box 395, Folder 5)
- Series XIV. Substance Use Counseling and Education Program, 1993-1997, n.d.; 4.25 boxes
  The Substance Use Counseling and Education (SUCE) program was created in 1993 and provided group counseling and education sessions for gay and bisexual men who felt that drugs and/or alcohol were affecting the decisions they made about sex. SUCE also produced educational materials regarding drug and alcohol use and safe sex.
  This series contains correspondence, memoranda, minutes, questionnaires, reports, and other material from the Substance Use Counseling and Education program at GMHC. The series is divided into two subseries: Administrative Files and Group Files. Audiovisual materials associate with these records can be found in Series XVI.B.5.
  - XIV. A. Administrative Files, 1993-1997; 3.25 boxes
    Included here are minutes and reports from the HIV Planning Council's Alcohol and Other Drugs Workgroup which developed SUCE, manuals for SUCE staff, questionnaires completed by SUCE participants, and notes on group sessions.
    - Brochures, 1995 (Box 395, Folder 6)
    - Client interview feedback, 1996 (Box 395, Folder 7)
    - Curriculum development with Project Connect, 1995 (Box 395, Folder 8)
    - Elovich, Richard, miscellaneous, 1994-1996 (Box 395, Folder 9)
    - Exit interviews
      - HIV negative, 1996 (Box 406, Folder 13)
      - HIV positive, 1996 (Box 407, Folder 1)
    - Expansion of department, 1993? (Box 395, Folder 10)
    - Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) proposals, 1993-1994 (Box 395, Folder 11)
    - HIV Planning Council
      - General, 1995 (Box 395, Folder 12-13)
      - Planning and Evaluation Committee, 1995 (Box 395, Folder 14)
      - Ryan White CARE Act Executive Committee, 1995 (Box 396, Folder 1)
    - Manuals
      - Harm Reduction and Steps Towards Change: A Training Source Book, 1995? (Box 396, Folder 2)
      - Recommended Reading, 1996-1997 (Box 396, Folder 3)
      - SUCE User's Manual and Process Evaluation Report, 1997 (Box 396, Folder 4-10)
    - Meeting notes, 1993-1995 (Box 397, Folder 1)
    - Memorandum, 1993 (Box 397, Folder 2)
    - Notes on SUCE forms, 1995 (Box 397, Folder 3)
    - Observer notes, 1995 (Box 397, Folder 4-7)
    - Participant case histories, 1996 (Box 407, Folder 2-4)
    - Postcards, 1995 (Box 398, Folder 1)
    - Prevention, 1996 (Box 398, Folder 2)
    - Program
      - Coordinators meetings, 1995 (Box 398, Folder 3)
      - Documents, 1994 (Box 398, Folder 4)
      - Feedback, 1995 (Box 398, Folder 5)
      - Flyers, 1993 (Box 398, Folder 6)
    - Recovery poster, undated (Box X-14)
    - Ryan White CARE Act
      - Alcohol and Other Drugs Workgroup, 1994-1995
        - General, 1994-1995 (Box 398, Folder 7)
        - Rikers project, 1993-1995 (Box 398, Folder 8-9)
      - Human Resources Administration (HRA) Division of AIDS Services, 1994 (Box 398, Folder 10)
      - Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) Guidance, 1994 (Box 398, Folder 11)
    - Staff meetings, 1995 (Box 398, Folder 12)
    - SUCE
      - Component description, 1995 (Box 398, Folder 13)
      - Evaluation plan, 1995 (Box 398, Folder 14)
      - Forms and materials, 1995 (Box 399, Folder 1)
      - Questionnaires, 1996-1997 (Box 399, Folder 2-5)
      - Substance use-related services for gay men and lesbians, 1994 (Box 399, Folder 6)
  - XIV. B. Groups, 1995-1997; 1 box
    This material includes feedback from and interviews with group participants and notes from SUCE group counselors.
    - Counselor group notes, 1996 (Box 399, Folder 7)
    - Ear point acupuncture, 1995? (Box 399, Folder 8)
    - Feedback Forums, Phases II and III, 1995 (Box 399, Folder 9)
    - Group notes, 1995-1997 (Box 399, Folder 10-12)
    - Group participant questionnaire, 1995 (Box 407, Folder 5-9)
- Series XV. Women's Education Services, 1991, 1994-1997, n.d; 1.75 boxes
  The Women's Education Services (WES) division of GMHC was created in 1996 and was an expansion of existing programs for women at GMHC. WES grew from the Lesbian AIDS Project, which became a part of WES but remained a distinct program. WES promoted existing GMHC programs for women, adapted programs aimed at heterosexual couples to the needs of lesbian, bisexual, and transgendered women, developed brochures and safe sex kits for women, and established support groups focusing on parenting and relationships.
  This series contains correspondence, memoranda, and other material from the Women's Education Services division of GMHC and is divided into two sections: Administrative Files and the Lesbian AIDS Project (LAP). LAP was created to conduct outreach to HIV positive lesbians, make them feel welcome at GMHC, and provide education and other services. Included in the Administrative Files are files on the creation of brochures for WES, the development of Women's Open Houses held at GMHC, and workshops for women. The LAP section contains manuals for workshops and memoranda on LAP Notes, the program's quarterly national newsletter.
  - Administrative Files, 1991, 1994-1997, n.d
    - Board of Directors meetings, 1997 (Box 400, Folder 1)
    - Bodega de la Familia, 1997 (Box 400, Folder 2)
    - Black and Latino AIDS Coalition, 1997 (Box 400, Folder 3)
    - Brochures, 1997 (Box 400, Folder 4)
    - Community Health Project, 1997 (Box 400, Folder 5)
    - Evaluation Research reviews of Women's Programs, 1994-1996 (Box 400, Folder 6)
    - Funding for Women's Programs, 1994, 1997 (Box 400, Folder 7)
    - Geffen Center, 1996-1997 (Box 400, Folder 8)
    - GMHC Education Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 400, Folder 9)
    - Lesbians and AIDS, 1996 (Box 401, Folder 1)
    - Memoranda, 1997 (Box 401, Folder 2)
    - Planning process, 1996-1997 (Box 401, Folder 3)
    - Women's Education Services groups, 1994, 1997 (Box 401, Folder 4)
    - Women's Open House at GMHC, 1996-1997 (Box 401, Folder 5-6)
    - Women's retreat proposal, 1997 (Box 401, Folder 7)
    - Workshops
      - Feeling Good All Over, 1997 (Box 401, Folder 8)
      - Negotiating Safer Sex, 1997? (Box 401, Folder 9)
      - Parenting Skills, 1997 (Box 401, Folder 10)
      - Spanish Phase II, 1991, n.d. (Box 401, Folder 11)
  - Lesbian AIDS Project, 1994-1997
    The Lesbian AIDS Project (LAP) was created in 1994 as part of the Education Department and became part of the Women's Education Services division in 1996. The purpose of LAP was to connect with HIV positive lesbians, make them welcome at GMHC, and provide education and other services.
    - Job readiness training, 1997 (Box 401, Folder 12)
    - Lesbians and HIV training curriculum, 1996 (Box 401, Folder 13)
    - Memoranda, 1994, 1997 (Box 401, Folder 14)
    - Safer sex workshops, 1995-1997 (Box 401, Folder 15)
    - Training guide, 1994 (Box 401, Folder 16)
- Series XVI. AudioVisual Department, 1985-1999, n.d.
  The Audiovisual Department was created to raise public awareness; serve as a means of communicating the medical, social, and psychological ramifications of the HIV/AIDS epidemic; and to support prevention and training programs. In addition to producing its own programming, the department assisted other GMHC departments by documenting training and creating promotional and outreach videos. The department, created in 1987, was staffed by an audiovisual specialist, Jean Carlomusto, and an assistant coordinator, Gregg Bordowitz. It was originally under the auspices of the Publications Department but then became part of the Education Department. In addition to Carlomusto and Bordowitz, other videographers represented in the collection are Marina Alvarez, Chas B. Brack, Sarah Cawley, Ronald Dodd, Andres J. Figueroa, Alexandra Juhasz, Juanita Mohammed, Ray Navarro, Steven Okazaki, Catherine Saalfield, Kristen Thomas, and Paul Zakrzewskiand.
  This series consists of 989 video recordings including both original footage and masters of completed works. GMHC produced broadcasted programs for television, oral histories, and miscellaneous programs to disseminate information about HIV/AIDS. The bulk of the material consists of original and unedited footage used for the Living with AIDS television show. Also represented are productions geared to specific cultural groups, young adults, interviews with PWAs, caretakers and other service providers, and films demonstrating safer sex practices.
  - XVI. A. Broadcast Productions
    This series includes productions created by the Audiovisual Department to be aired regularly on public access television. The department ran three different series: AIDS Network, Outreach, and Living with AIDS. These broadcast productions represent the bulk of the department's efforts; this series contains the majority of raw footage found this collection, most notably the original, unedited interviews.
    - XVI. A. 1. AIDS Network
      AIDS Network was a thirty-minute program that aired on public access television and was a precursor to the Living with AIDS show. Each show was introduced by Lori Behrman and included live interviews with caretakers, service providers and PWAs. All videos in this sub-series are mastered productions of aired episodes of AIDS Network.
      - Show #1, 1985 Dec 16; 980; 1 videocassette
        Behrman. Request for Donations. Credits Jerry Johnson Interview. Resource Spot with Tom Miller. Bill Messina Interview. Lori
      - Show #2, 1985 Dec 23; 981; 1 videocassette
        Phil Zwickler. John Martich
      - Show #3, 1985 Dec, 1986 Jan; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
        Inteviews with Audrey Hassel and Bob Lugo.
      - Show #5, 1986 Jan; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
        Interviews with John Martich and Bonnie Primm.
      - Show #7, 1986 Oct; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
        Interviews with Richard Dunne and Victor Bumbalo.
      - Show #8, 1986 Feb; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
        Interviews with Dolores Smithies and Patrick Hacker.
      - Show #9, 1986 Feb; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
        Interview with Victor Bumbalo and Audrey Hassel.
      - Show #10, 1986 Sep; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
        Interviews with Sara Mercado, Lee Pleva and Griffen Gold.
      - Show #11, 1986 Feb 4; 982; 1 videocassette
        Interviews with Bob Cecchi, GMHC Ombudsman, and Brent Nicholson Earle, founder of A.R.E.A.
      - Show #12, 1986 Mar; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
        Interviews with Phyllis Gurdin, on foster care of HIV positive children, and Dolores Smithies, a social worker and GMHC volunteer.
      - Show #13, 1986 Sep-Oct; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
        Interviews with Mark Senak, of GMHC's Legal Services, and Malcolm MacKay from New York Life Insurance.
      - Show #14, 1986 Mar 17; 983; 1 videocassette
        Interviews with Raymond Jacobs, John Lewis and Fred Gormley about the production of "Chance of a Lifetime".
      - Show #15- The Hospice Show, 1986 Aug 25; 984; 1 videocassette
        Paul Zakrzewski interviews Sister Patrice Murphy, Carole Donovan, R.N., and Kathleen Perry, M.S.W., of the St. Vincent's Hospital Hospice Program.
      - Show #16, 1986 Mar 31; 985; 1 videocassette
        Paul Zakrzewski interviews Charles McKinney, director of the GMHC Education Department.
      - Show #17, 1986 Apr 14; 986; 1 videocassette
        Lori Behrman interviews Joseph Foulon about the AIDS Walk and Paul Kawata of the National AIDS Network.
      - Show #17, 1986 Sep 1; 987; 1 videocassette
        Interviews with David Summers, a PWA, and Peter Avitabile, David Wayne and Beth Broderick of St. Peter's Tuesday Yoga/Massage recreation workshop.
      - Show #18, 1986 Apr 21; 988; 1 videocassette
        Paul Zakrzewski interviews Chuck McKinney.
      - Show #21, 1986; ---; 2 videocassettes (unavailable)
        Interviews by Paul Zakrzewski. Date reflects when program was aired. uncut original
      - Show #21- Alternative Therapies, 1986 Sep 15; 990; 1 videocassette
        Paul Zakrzewski interviews Max Navarre.Resource Spot Tom Miller. Lori Behrman interviews Lee Pleva.
      - Show #24- AIDS-related complex (ARC), 1986 Oct 20; 991; 1 videocassette
        Interview with Jeannetta Bushey.
      - Show #25, 1986 Jul; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
        Interviews with Lee Kotchems, GMHCs Research Program Director and Dore Keller, from the anti-violence project. Diane Ponzio sings song "Nobody Wants to Hug my Brother".
      - Show #26, 1986 Jul 28; 992; 1 videocassette
        Interviews with Kris Gannon and John Glines.
      - Show #27, 1986 Aug; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
        Paul Zakrzewski interviews three gay clergymen, Rev. Tim Marshall, Rev. James Gardiner and Father William Hart.
      - Show #30, 1986 Oct; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
        Interview with Louise Hay.
      - Show #31, 1986 Oct 13; 993; 1 videocassette
        Interviews with Richard Dunne and Patrick Hacker.
    - XVI. A. 2. Outreach
      This subseries contains aired episodes of Outreach on video tapes. In addition to the standard show format, there are two episodes called Caring in Times of Crisis and and Epidemic Center Stage. Caring focuses on volunteers and the organization they work for and Epidemic is a theater performance of excerpts from four plays about AIDS.
      - Caring in Times of Crisis, undated; ---; 2 videocassettes (unavailable)
        Also includes early version of GMHC's training film, "The Intake Interview". Kevin Mahony interviews Barbara Grande on her volunteer work in crisis intervention and Scott Jordan on Operation Speakout. Richard Dunne interviews Judith Peabody, volunteer and financial donor. Produced by Jean Carlomusto Scott Jordan interviews Lester Abrams, coordinator of the Telephone Team, George Getzel, PWA support group leader, and Robert Bolton and Carole Lemmons, from the A-Team (a community counseling group).
      - Compiled material, undated; ---; 3 videocassettes (unavailable)
        Includes interviews with Bruce Anderson, Jim Holmes, Kevin Madden, Joey Leonte, Lee Kochems, Rodger MacFarlane, Bruce Patterson, Scott Jordan, Joseph Foulon, Luis Palacios-Jimenez, David Sommers, Stash Santora, Marilyn Kach, Sister Kathleen O'Farrell, Doug Marcino, Steve McFadden, and Casey Donovan.
      - Epidemic Center Stage, 1987 Apr. 27; ---; 10 videocassettes (unavailable)
        Ellen Stewart Event sponsored by GMHC and the Fund for Human Dignity 1987 Writer in Residence Program. Hosted by Raymond Jacobs and Darrell Yates-Rist. Interview by Kevin Mahony
    - XVI. A. 3. Living With AIDS
      Living with AIDS was a thirty-minute program that aired regularly on public access television and sought to provide quality programming to people with AIDS. The first episode aired in 1987 and the series ran until 1997. Initially the show was filmed as either a short documentary or as a live show with a panel of guests discussing a single topic, but overtime it evolved into more of a magazine-based format, each show being made up of 8-10 minute segments. The shows were repackaged and reaired in a changing combination of segments. These segments were topical in nature, broad in scope and content, covering a variety of topics such as healthcare and treatment; activism; risk reduction strategies; raising families; and maintaining relationships. Recurring segments were Medical Updates, which provided users with up to the minute treatment information and updates on medical issues in other countries, such as Germany and Japan; and Video Portraits, which were short portrayals of individuals who were infected or affected by AIDS.
      This subseries contains the documentary style shows, live shows and segments of Living with AIDS, arranged in one general run alphabetically. It also includes focus group sessions on audio tapes. The focus groups were part of a study to ascertain how people received information about AIDS and their opinions on the Living with AIDS show. Also included are videos that were produced by unrelated videographers and screened during GMHC programs, such as John Greyson's The Pink Pimpernel and The World is Sick".
      - 10 Years of 10k, undated; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
      - ACT UP United Nations Protest and Washington Civil, undated; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
      - AIDS Quilt, 1996 Oct 12; ---; 3 videocassettes (unavailable)
      - AIDS Walkathon 1987, ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
        Produced by Jean Carlomusto
      - AIDS Walkathon 1988, ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)
      - AIDS Walkathon 1989, ---; 5 videocassettes (unavailable)
      - AIDS Walkathon 1998, 1998 Apr 9; ---; 1 videocassette (unavailable)